Hello welcome to this part of physics this is intended to be the first course in physics which is
Concerned with the study of the properties of matter including motion
Power of the portal and systems of Pasco
I am Professor Cinema
A professor of physics at University university is situated in heaven
A town in Jordan and I thought the physics courses ranging from freshman to
Graduate-level courses in different aspects
The course material
Will include various aspects as a mansion
The first chapter
What would be naturally concerned with measurements
And units used for that purpose
And this also includes
Factor analysis for four quantities which need the direction to be specifically
Also this course will include
A chapter concerned with the description of motion of a single particle or an object which
Wolves like the motion of a single particle meaning if we endure the effects of rotation and changing the size of someone
The shape of the object also
This course will be concerned is the third chapter
With the study of the Dynamics of a particle or an object simulating the motion of a single particle
This field is concerned with the
Relation between the motion and the causes of the motion
Off the system of particles under consideration
The 4th chapter of this course will be concerned with the study of the system
Of particles in an object we apply in that span the same rules and principles of a
In the Peter chapter 2 study Costco
He sits chapter of the scores will be concerned with the study of
Motion of rigid bodies in the game we rely on the same principles and methods
Save Alex chapter 2 study the motion of rigid body
Chapter 6 will be concerned with the study of the motion of fluids ticular Lee ideal fluid
And finally the 7th chapter of the course will be concerned with the study of hair Medina
Mechanical properties of material
In this first person
We are concerned with the study
Of the units and standard used for measurement
The first lecture will be focusing on units and standard
Second rupture of this chapter will
Be concerned with the analysis
In this lecture we will first